Guide to the Dr. Huey P. Newton Foundation Inc. Collection
Department of Special Collections
- Series 7: Printed materials, 7
  - The Sixties The Decade Remebered Now, by the People Who Lived It Then editied by Lynda Rosen Obst1977 (Othertype 8, Folder 2)
    Rolling Stone publication
  - The African World - newspaper1972 - 1975 (Othertype 9, Folder 1)
    May 27, 1972, vol. 2, no. 6; Dec. 9, 1972, vol. 3, no. 4; Jun. 30 - Oct. 1973, vol. 3, nos. 16-21, 24; Mar. 1974 - Nov. 30, 1974, vol. 4, nos. 2-6; May 1975, vol. 4, no. 9
  - Afrikan Awakener - newspaper1974 - 1975 (Othertype 9, Folder 2)
    Jul. 15, 1974, vol. 1, no. 6; May 31, 1975, vol. 2, no.10.
  - Anvil - newspaper (Othertype 9, Folder 3)
    August
  - The Burning Spear - newspaper1987 (Othertype 9, Folder 4)
    Apr. 1987, vol. 14, no. 1
  - California Voice- newspaper1990 (Othertype 9, Folder 5)
    Mar. 9, 1990, vol. 71, no. 4
  - The Communist- newspaper1974 - 1975 (Othertype 9, Folder 6)
    Oct. 15 - Nov. 15, 1974, vol. 1, nos 3 - 4; Apr. - May 24, 1975, vol. 1, nos.7 - 8; Jul. 8 - 25, 1975, vol. 1, no. 10
  - The Conspiracy - newspaper1970 (Othertype 9, Folder 7)
    Sep. 1970, vol. 1, no. 1
  - Express - newspaper1989 (Othertype 9, Folder 8)
    Sept. 15, 1989, vol. II, no. 49
  - Good Times - newspaper1970 (Othertype 9, Folder 9)
    Feb. 19, 1970, vol. 3, no. 18
  - Good Times - newspaper1970 (Othertype 9, Folder 10)
    Jun. 19, 1970, vol. 3, no. 25
  - Habari - newspaper (Othertype 9, Folder 11)
  - Jihad News - newspaper1976 (Othertype 9, Folder 12)
    Sept. - Oct. 1976
  - The Movement- newspaper1966; 1968 (Othertype 9, Folder 13)
    Jun. 1966, vol. 2, no. 4; Apr, Jun 1968, vol. 4, nos. 3 - 5
  - Muhammad Speaks - newspaper1973 - 1974 (Othertype 9, Folder 14)
    Mar. 30, 1973, vol. 12, no. 29; Apr. 12, 1974, vol. 13, no. 3
  - Newspaper article1989 (Othertype 9, Folder 15)
    Aug. 27, 1989
  - New World Film Society - newspaper1975 (Othertype 9, Folder 16)
    May 25, 1975
  - Pamoja Venceremos - newspaper1971 (Othertype 10, Folder 1)
    Sept. 1-9, 1971, no.8
  - People's World - newspaper1970 (Othertype 10, Folder 2)
    Feb. 14, 1970
  - Prisoners Union on Strike - newspaper (Othertype 10, Folder 3)
  - Rolling Stone - newspaper1982 (Othertype 10, Folder 4)
    Jun. 24, 1982, no. 372
  - San Francisco Bay Guardian - newspaper1975; 1978 (Othertype 10, Folder 5)
    Mar. 7, 1975, vol. 9, no. 9; Jun. 1-9, 1978, vol. 12, no. 33
  - San Francisco Chronicle - newspaper1989 (Othertype 10, Folder 6)
    Aug. 23-24, 26, 1989, nos. 188-89, 191.
  - San Francisco Examiner - newspaper1970 (Othertype 10, Folder 7)
    Aug. 8, 1970, vol. 1970, no. 32
  - San Francisco Examiner - newspaper1989 (Othertype 10, Folder 8)
    Aug. 23, 27, 1989
  - San Francisco Express Times - newspaper1968 (Othertype 10, Folder 9)
    Apr. 18, 1968
  - San Jose Mercury News - newspaper1990 (Othertype 10, Folder 10)
    Aug. 19, 1990
  - Santa Cruz Independent - newspaper1978 (Othertype 10, Folder 11)
    Oct. 26 - Nov. 1, 1978, vol. 3, no. 16
  - Sun/Dance- newspaper1970 (Othertype 10, Folder 12)
    Oct. 1970, issue 2
  - The Sun Reporter - newspaper1976; 1989; 1990 (Othertype 10, Folder 13)
    Jan. 31 - Mar. 27, 1976; Oct. 25, 1989, vol. 45, no. 43; Aug. 22, 1990, vol. 46, no. 34.
  - The Sun Reporter - newspaper1990 (Othertype 10, Folder 14)
    Mar. 7, 1990, vol. 46, no. 10
  - The Tribune - newspaper1989; 1990 (Othertype 10, Folder 15)
    Aug. 23-24, 26, 29, 1989; Jul. 4, 1990; Aug. 25-26, 1990.
  - United Front News - newspaper1972 (Othertype 10, Folder 16)
    Jun. 3, 1972 [two copies]
  - Wassaja - newspaper1973 (Othertype 10, Folder 17)
    Feb/Mar, 1973, vol. 1, no. 2.
  - A movement of New World Women [poster]: a series of events by and about women of color and the violence against us / [presented by] The Women of Color Caucus of New York Women Against Rape. (Othertype 10, Folder 18)
- Series 8: Newspaper Clippings, 8
  - New Orleans, LA. Paper January 6, 19401940; 1970s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Newsclips 1968 Huey Newton Trial and Protests]1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Huey P. Newton - Local Newspapers on Race Indicating Press for Two Weeks Prior to Trial and to July 26, 19681968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [Newspaper clippings] [1968 - 1969]1968 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings - Misc. [1 of 2] [1968 - 1970]1968 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings - Misc. [2 of 2] [1968 - 1976]1968 - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - New Haven Trial Newspaper Articles [1 of 2]1970 - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - New Haven Trial Newspaper Articles [2 of 2]1970 - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Judge Drops Charges Against Seale & Huggins - Associated Press - New Haven, CT. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Articles on BPP Trials [1970 - 1971]1970 - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Various Newsclips: B.P. Newsletter; Bobby Seale Trial; David Frost Show Appearance, etc. [1 of 2] [1970 - 1972]1969 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Various Newsclips: B.P. Newsletter; Bobby Seale Trial; David Frost Show Appearance, etc. [2 of 2] [1970 - 1972]1969 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A Panther Shout-Out - S.F. Examiner - March 7, 19711971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Los Siete Trial1971 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cairo, Illinois [March 1971]1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Articles on Party Cases (general) [1 of 2] [May 1971 - 1972]1970 - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Articles on Party Cases (general) [2 of 2] [May 1971 - 1974]1970 - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fred Bennett [ June 14, 1971]1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Servants Visit to the People's Republic of China [Oct. 1971 - Mar. 1972]1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Weatherman [Nov. 1971]1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nixon in the People's Republic of China [Nov. 1971 - Feb. 1972]1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Newton Case Mistrial - Oakland Tribune- Dec. 12, 1971 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - On the People's Republic of China [Dec. 1971 - Feb. 1972]1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Attica State Prison [1971]1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sweet Sweetback's Baadasssss Song [1971]1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Black Panther Party and the Church [1971]1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - [Miscellaneous newspapers and serials] [1 of 2] [1971]1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - [Miscellaneous newspapers and serials] [2 of 2] [1969]1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - News Clippings - Various1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings (1971) (16) CRG #8590 [1 of 2]1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings (1971) (16) CRG #8590 [2 of 2]1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mahammad Ali - Joe Frazier Fight1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Articles Regarding the Boycott1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The People's Republic of China has a seat in the United Nations 1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Rap Brown [Oct. 1971 - June 1972] (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Black P. Stone Nation1971 - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Algiers Defection1971 - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper / Xerox Clippings1971; 1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - General Articles (file 1 of file 1 and 2) [1 of 2] [1971 - 1972]1971 - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General Articles (file 1 of file 1 and 2) [2 of 2] [1972 - 1973]1972 - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Write-ups on the Party (file 2, of file 1 and 2)1971 - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General Articles (file 2, of file 1 and 2) [1 of 2]1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - General Articles (file 2, of file 1 and 2) [2 of 2]1972 - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Voter Registration Drive [Jan. - Mar. 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Nixon in the People's Republic of China [Feb. 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Muslims [Feb. - July 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - March 29, 30 & 31: Black Community Survival Conference [Mar. - Apr. 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Marlon Scott vs. The Servant and R. Bay [Apr. - May 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Wallace Shooting [May 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Murders in Vietnam [May 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Ron Dellums [May 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Shirley Chisholm [May - July 1972]1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Survival Conference June 24, 19721972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Release of Hilliard on Parole Urged - Richmond Post Oct. 19, 1972 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Examining the Adult Authority - Freedom News December '72 1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Murder of Comrade Samuel Napier1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - James E. Carr1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Death Penalty1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cable Info1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Panthers Elected to Berkeley Anti-Poverty Program1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Common Ground - Reviews, Promotions, etc.1972 - 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General Write-ups on the Party [1 of 2]1972 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General Write-ups on the Party [2 of 2]1972 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Charges of Unfairness - BP Inmate Vacaville, CA Reporter - Jan 22, 1973 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Quaker Blames Unrest on Adult Authority Sacramento Bee - Jan. 18, 1973 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Top Prison Aides Draw Criticism - Times Herald Vallejo Jan 18, 1973 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Denial of Parole for Hilliard - S.F. Chronicle Jan-Feb 1973 1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Gurus---Maharaj Ji, etc. [July 1973]1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General Write-ups on Oakland [Sept. 1973 - May 1974]1973 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Watergate1973 - 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hilliard Falls From Grace - Bay Guardian - Apr. 27, 1974 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The S.L.A.1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Drug Problem [Aug. 1974 / June - July 1976]1974 - 1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - The Fox Bust -- Newton, Heard, etc.1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fred Hampton / Mark Clark [Feb. - May 1976]1976 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - General Articles [May 1976 - March 1977]1976 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - FBI Director, J. Edgar Hoover [May 1976 - Dec. 1977]1976 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Oakland Mayor Race [July 1976 - February 1977]1976 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - San Quentin Six [Aug. 1976]1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Andrew Young [Dec. 1976]1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Articles Re: Death Penalty Law1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - General Articles on Oakland [Dec. 1976 - Jan. 1977]1976 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - B.P.P. $100 Million Suit (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Articles Done While in Cuba1976 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - [Newspaper Clippings] [1 of 2] 1976 - 1978 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - [Newspaper Clippings] [2 of 2] 1976 - 1978 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Roots - Alex Haley [January - February 1977]1977 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Grove-Shafter & City Center Projects [Feb. 1977]1977 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Black Panther Newspaper Vol XVI No.20 Mar. 26, 19771977 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - General Articles Done by Huey After July Return to the U.S. 19771977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Huey and Gwen Articles Re: 1977, July Return to U.S.1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Whites Did not enter Davis under Minority Admissions - Daily Californian - Oct. 6, 1977 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Elaine Brown resigns from B.P.P. [Nov. 1977]1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cuba [Nov. 1977]1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General Articles on the BPP1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Articles Re: 1977 Trials [Oct. 1977 - Jan. 1978]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings [1 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings [2 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings [3 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings [4 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings [5 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings [6 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings [7 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings [8 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings [9 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings [10 of 10]1977 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Newton, Huey P. Clip File [Feb. 1978]1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - HPN: Old Battles, New Times - Santa Cruz Independent 10/26-11/1 1978 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The Lighter Side of Huey - Santa Cruz Independent 11/9-15/78 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - [Le Monde Diplomatique] [Dec. 1978]1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous1978 - 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - [News Clippings and Magazines] [1 of 2] 1978 - 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - [News Clippings and Magazines] [2 of 2] 1979 - 1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Plotted to Smear Her Actress (J. Seberg) Says FBI 2/8/791979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Why E. Cleaver is a Wife Beater - S.F. Chronicle May 13, 1980 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings: San Jose Mercury / Huey get Doctorate 6/15/801980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1978 Santa Cruz Case [June 1980]1978 - 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - About Oakland Nov. 1980 No.71980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Making of a Chinese Dissident - SF Chronicle, Nov. 18, 1980 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Gang of Four Case - Beijing - San Francisco Chronicle Nov. 18, 1980 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - A Critic of Judges Becomes One Himself - S.F. Chronicle Nov. 30, 1980 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Universal Life Church Vol. XV No.1 March 19811981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Howard Hunt Allowed to Have Gun - S.F. Chronicle July 9, 1981 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Life After the Bench Paul Halvonik - L.A. Journal Aug. 10, 1981 1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - HPN Talks of Booze and Boredom - S.F. Chronicle Nov 5, 1984 1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Newspaper Articles on Huey P. Newton1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper: Oakland Tribune - Huey Newton's Funeral - Aug. 29, 1989 1989 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Suspect / Huey Newton's Killer - Oakland Tribune Tues. Aug. 29, 1989 1989 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Plight of America's Young Black Men - Oakland Tribune Aug.29, 1989 1989 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - H.P.N. Eulogized as a Hero - S.F. Chronicle Aug. 29, 1989 1989 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Huey P. Newton / Dissertation [news clipping after his death] [ Aug. 1989]1989 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Express Newspaper Article on Huey P. Newton's Death [Sept. 1989]1989 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Former BPP Members Start New Group - S.F. Chronicle Dec. 8, 1989 1989 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Alabama's Black Belt Activism - Guardian -Feb.21, 19901990 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Rebirth of the BPP by Hugh Pearson - S.F. Weekly April 4, 1990 1990 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Black Panthers: A Look Back - S.F. Chronicle - May 30, 1990 1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Paris Picks Up on Panther Pride - S.F. Datebook Aug 19, 1990 1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - One Year after Huey P. Newton's Death - Oakland Tribune Article [Aug. 1990]1990 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Blacks Try to Rebuild Their Past - L.A. Times - Septmeber 22, 1990 1990 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - From Black Panthers to White-Shoe Firm - K. Cleaver - American Lawyer - Oct. 1990 1990 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - The Commemorator Vol.1 No.1 Nov. 19901990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - 20 Years Later- David and Bobby Rush - The Final Call Dec. 10, 1990 1990 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - [Copies of newspaper articles of HPN's death]1991 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - David Hilliard Speaking, The Beacon North Adams State at Mass., Nov. 4, 19931993 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Newspaper Clippings Re: David's Book [1 of 2]1993 - 1994 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Newspaper Clippings Re: David's Book [2 of 2]1993 - 1994 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper Articles '941994 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - This Side of Glory - David Hilliard - Berkeley Metro Reporter 1/30/94 1994 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - David Hilliard Lectures at Mass. - The Torch (Univ. Of Mass., Dartmouth) Feb. 14, 1994 1994 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - A Graying Panther- David Hilliard - Detroit Free Press, Feb. 16, 19941994 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Review of "This Side of Glory" - Chicago Tribune Feb. 27, 1994 1994 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Van Peebles on "Panther" - Exodus, July 12-27 1994 1994 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Revival of Panthers - LA Sentinel, Oct. 26, 1994 1994 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - B.P. Mural Backers Reject Funding - L.A. Times - Oct. 27, 19941994 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Beyond the Gun - David Hilliard - Sonoma County Independent Nov. 3, 1994 1994 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Key Witness Discredited in Huey Newton Frame Up (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Sun Reporter Article HPN Victim of Les Miserables Syndrome1981 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - New Haven Trial Newspaper Articles1971 (Othertype 7, Folder 1)
- Series 9: Huey P. Newton Foundation Files, 9
  - [BPP Materials]1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Microfilming - Archive Project1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Microfilm Proposal re: Equipment Microreader 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mindseed Corporation1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    CD-Rom and microfilming opportunities
  - Murder in Miniature Yummy Sandifer - age 111993 - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    copies of newspaper articles regarding the foundation and the history of the panthers
  - Multi-Service Center Contract - Red Cross & City of Oakland1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gus Newport (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Biographical sketch of Eugene "Gus" Newport
  - New African Amer Vanguard Movement - L.A.1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Luminare Joint Venture1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Malcolm X Article 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Maxine Waters on Elizabeth Catlett (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Michael Levy - Thesis on Social and Personal Change1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MLK Redevelopment Plan [Martin Luther King Drive adopted by the Municipal Court]1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Papers Project at Stanford (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Middle Passage Memorial1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    also includes a documentary film proposal, "Spirit of the Panther: the Story and Vision of Huey P. Newton" and an article "Sally Hemings and Thomas Jefferson: the Love Story that Belongs to Us All" by Barbara Chase-Riboud
  - [Listing of video clips from HPN's funeral] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ["Panther", by Melvin Van Peebles]1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mario Van Peebles - Books1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mike Tyson Letter1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mickey's Faxes - Various [Mickey Phillips]1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Helen Merrill, Ltd. 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Voyager Publishing Co.
  - Political/articles Speeches1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)